Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
With a chest made of rubble, I can't even breathe.
gareki no mune iki mo dekinai
The rain starts to fall, like a slumbering cry.
furidasu ame nemuru you ni cry
What flower should I decorate myself with
kono sekai o ikinuku no naraba
To stay alive in this world?
donna hana o kazareba ii no?
I want to believe, but still can't manage it...
shinjitai kuse ni shinjirarezu ni
My powerless and pointless self
muryoku de muimi na jibun ga
Still embraces my heart.
soredemo kokoro de idakun da
I can hear a voice calling to me, saying, "Come this way!"
"kocchi e oide" to koe ga kikoeru
A limitless and reckless tomorrow
mugen de mubou na ashita ga
Will still be waiting for me somewhere.
soredemo dokoka de matsu kara
Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
（チセ）死ぬ… 私が？
Death?
My death?
（アリス）夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)は
Sleigh Beggies are treasures,
in that you create an unending supply of magic,
尽きることなく
魔力を生み出す宝石だ
but your bodies are very fragile.
けど その体は とてももろい
生きているだけで際限なく
魔力の吸収と生産を繰り返し
Just being alive,
you relentlessly absorb and generate magic.
Eventually, your body will buckle.
やがて
体が負荷に耐えられなくなる
You're well-versed in the matter, Alice.
（レンフレッド）
よく理解している アリス
（アリス）いえ
Not really.
（レンフレッド）
危険な状態にある君を
He keeps you alive without taking
any measures to help you out of danger,
あいつは自分の興味本位で
何の処置もせず生かしている
just to satiate his own curiosity.
That dizziness...
（チセ）
あの めまい…
Chise-kun, he has no feelings.
チセ君 あいつに情などないんだよ
You can't expect human
kindness from a sham of a human.
人間気取りの まがいものに
人間らしい好意を
期待してはいけない
He bought you with money
and tied you down with that thing.
金で買われ
そんなもので縛られて…
追跡の術がかけてあるな
He has a tracking spell on it.
つらかっただろう
You must have suffered.
（レンフレッド）
私たちが君を自由にしてあげよう
We'll set you free.
Ariel!
（チセ）エアリエル！
Master!
（ジャスパーとバーニー）ニャー！
This place is our territory.
（モリィ）ここは我々の縄張りだ
魔術師風情が
しゃしゃり出ないでもらおう！
I won't have sorcerers wandering around here.
Are you all right, Ariel?
（チセ）大丈夫？ エアリエル
Yes, I'm fine, as long as I'm not touching metal.
鉄から離れれば何ともないわン
Why?
なぜだ
君は解放されたくないのか？
Don't you want to be set free?
From what?
（チセ）何から？
If you mean from Elias,
you probably wouldn't understand.
エリアスからだとしたら
あなたは多分 理解しない
Even if he was lying,
he was the only one to ever call me family.
たとえ うそでも
私を家族と言ったのはエリアスだけ
I don't care whether you were lying or telling the truth.
あなたの言ったことが
うそでも本当でも どっちでもいい
He was the first person to value me.
あの人は誰よりも先に私を買った
So until Elias lets go of my hand,
だから
エリアスが私の手を離すまでは…
私は あの人のものです
I belong to him.
（アリス）くっ！
（レンフレッド）アリス！
Alice!
Have you forgotten?
（エリアス）忘れたのか　僕は影
I am shadow.
I lurk in the shadows of thorns.
茨(いばら)の影に潜むもの
I am what you call the Pilum Murialis.
お前たちが
裂き喰らう城(ピルム･ムーリアリス)と呼ぶもの
Are you all right, Chise?
大丈夫？ チセ
（チセ）はい
Yes.
Can I see your wound?
（エリアス）傷 見せて
My wound?
（チセ）傷？
That was reckless of you.
（エリアス）むちゃするなあ
Ouch...
（チセ）痛っ…
（エリアス）
人間は
傷ついたら すぐ死んじゃうからね
You humans don't last very long once you're injured.
（エアリエル）
来んのが遅い！
影なのに影が薄い！
You're late!
You're a pale shadow of a shadow!
Chise was here.
（エリアス）
チセがいたんだ しかたないだろ
What could I do?
Its bonds are coming loose.
（エリアス）縛りが解けそうだ
Chise, I'll take care of things here.
チセ ここは大丈夫だから
こいつと浄化をお願い
I'll leave the cleansing to you two.
Yes.
はい
I'll come with you.
（モリィ）私も行きましょう
King!
（２匹）王！
You don't have to worry about it.
（エアリエル）
心配しなくても大丈夫よン
アタシとチセがやるんだからン
Chise and I are going to handle it.
（モリィ）
この澱(よど)みが消えてうせるのなら
It's the final duty of the king
to see that the corruption is gone.
その様を見届けるのが
最後の王の務め
そうでしょう？
Is it not?
Chise!
（エアリエル）チセ…
チセ 大丈夫？
Are you all right?
ここは…
Where are we?
A tavern from long ago.
はるか昔のタヴァン
食事処(どころ)ですわね
A place to eat.
The neighboring town was beautiful.
（男性Ａ）
いや 隣町 スゲえきれいだったぜ
I heard there are a lot of beautiful women there, too.
（男性Ｂ）
べっぴんさんも多いらしいしな
（チセ）透けてる…
I can see through myself.
It looks like we're inside the corruption's memories.
（エアリエル）
ここは澱みの記憶の中みたいねン
That man...
（チセ）
あの人…
Thank you very much.
Hey, are you the wandering sorcerer?
（マシュー）
なあ 流しの魔術師って あんたか？
（カルタフィルス）ああ そうだよ
Yeah, that's me.
こんなチビで びっくりしたかい？
Are you surprised that I'm so small?
何か相談でも？
Did you need some help?
分かるのか？
You can tell?
People everywhere depend on me when I'm traveling.
旅をしていると
あちらこちらで頼られるからね
Bad harvests?
畑が不作？
Trying to win a special lady's attention?
ほれてる娘に
振り向いてもらいたい？
No, my wife's always been frail.
いや… うちのヤツが
生まれつき体が弱くて
She always ends up bedridden.
どうにも すぐ寝込むんだ
I want her to become healthier.
何とか
元気になってもらいたいんだが
いい薬とか… 何かないだろうか
Do you have medicine or anything that'll help?
ふ〜ん…
奥方を とても好いてるんだね
You must care a lot about your wife.
（マシュー）もちろんだ！
Obviously!
That was a fast reply.
即答かい
恥ずかしい男だねえ 君…
You're an embarrassing man.
May I see your wife in person?
奥方を 直接 診せてもらっても？
Yes, please.
ああ！ 頼む すぐ来てくれ！
Come soon.
He's no good.
（チセ）
あれは… 嫌なやつだ
（カルタフィルス）ふむ…
Thank you.
ありがとう　もう休みな
Get some rest.
I'll go talk to your husband.
ご主人と お話ししてくるよ
Okay.
（ミナ）はい
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
So, how is it?
（マシュー）で… どうなんだ？
（ミナ）ティム？ ティム？
Tim?
Tim.
What's wrong, Tim?
どうしたの？ ティム
I don't think she'll get any better than she is.
（カルタフィルス）
恐らく あれ以上に
良くなることはないだろうね
She won't last more than a few years.
もって あと数年だろう
She was born that way.
生まれつきだ　しょうがないな
Can't be helped.
No...
（マシュー）そんな…
ミ… ミナは 昔から外で遊べもせず
M-Mina couldn't even play outside as a child.
根は働き者なのに
She's hard-working in spirit,
but she can't do much because of her health!
体のせいで ままならない
かわいそうなヤツなんだ！
She deserves better!
俺にできることなら
何でもやるから！
I'll do anything for her!
Please!
お願いだ
このまま死ぬなんて
かわいそうすぎる…
I couldn't bear to see her die!
（カルタフィルス）ふ〜ん…
奥方 猫は好きかい？
Does your wife like cats?
（マシュー）え… 猫？
Cats?
Sure.
I see.
（カルタフィルス）
そうかあ　なら ちょうどいいかも
That's perfect, then!
知ってるかい？
猫には９つの命があるんだ
Have you heard that cats have nine lives?
（村人）あっ またネズミか！
More rats!
Is it just me, or are there lots of rats lately?
（村娘Ａ）
最近 ネズミが多くないかい？
（村娘Ｂ）
猫たちが仕事をサボッてるのかねえ
I suppose the cats aren't doing their jobs.
（村娘Ｃ）おや… ミナ！
Mina.
Are you sure you're well enough to be up and about?
起きてて大丈夫なのかい？
Yes, the weather's nice today.
ええ 今日は天気もいいから
Have you seen Matthew?
ねえ マシューを見なかった？
I went to bring him a meal, but he wasn't in the field.
ご飯を届けに行ったんだけど
畑にいなかったの
Maybe he's out meeting a woman.
（村娘Ａ）
どっかの誰かと逢引(あいびき)してたりして〜
Don't be silly!
（村娘Ｃ）
バカなことを お言いでないよ！
Everyone knows Matthew's all about Mina.
マシューが
ミナ 一筋なのは…
I saw him go into the forest with an axe.
（村娘Ｂ）
さっき 森に
斧(おの) 持って入ってったよ
I was just joking!
（ミナ）森？
The forest?
Matthew!
（ミナ）マシュー！
マシュー
Chise, are you okay?
（エアリエル）
チセ 大丈夫？
顔色すっごい悪いわよン
You look really pale.
I have a really bad feeling about this.
すごく… 嫌な予感がする
（ミナ）
小屋？
こんな所に小屋なんてあったかしら
A shed?
Was there always a shed here?
No!
（チセ）
いけない！
What's that Matthew up to?
マシューったら何してるのかしら
Matthew?
マシュー
（チセ）
いけない！
No!
（ミナ）マシュー
Matthew.
No!
（チセ）
いけない
Don't look inside!
中を見ちゃ…
Matthew.
マシュー
Mina.
ミナ
Ah, you're doing well today.
（マシュー）
ああ 今日は具合がいいんだな
Perfect.
ちょうどよかった
今 完成したところだったんだよ
I just finished making this.
It's your medicine.
君のための薬が
Medicine?
（ミナ）薬？
Matthew, what are you...
マシュー 何を…
何を言ってるの？
What are you talking about?
Remember we had a sorcerer see you?
この間
魔術師に診てもらっただろ？
この霊薬を作って 君に飲ませれば
He told me that this potion would make you better.
元気になるって教えてもらったんだ
Th-These cats...
（ミナ）
ね… 猫は？ この猫たちは…
Where did these cats come from?
（マシュー）ああ 材料だよ
They're ingredients.
They say cats have nine lives.
猫には９つの命があるって言うけど
Apparently it's true.
あれは本当なんだって
He said I could make you medicine out of the cats' lives.
だから 猫たちの命を集めて
薬を作れるって
How unfair is it that these beasts have so many lives?
ズルいよな
こんなケダモノが
たくさんの命を持ってるなんて
（ミナ）
マシュー！
ねえ マシュー どうしたの？
Matthew!
Hey, what happened to you?!
How could you do such a terrible thing?!
なんで
こんなひどいことできたの？
あなた こんなこと
できる人じゃないでしょ！
You aren't the kind of person who could do this!
（マシュー）できるよ
I can.
Because...
だって…
It's for your sake.
君のためだから
Matthew...
マシュー
I can't move.
（ミナ）
体が動かない…
You don't have to be scared.
（カルタフィルス）
大丈夫だよ 怖がらなくて
それを飲めば
君は 不自由な体から自由になれる
Drink that, and you'll go
from being weak to able-bodied.
You might even be able to live forever.
それどころか
永遠の命さえ手に入るかも
You...
（ミナ）
あなた… マシューに何を…
What have you done to Matthew?!
（カルタフィルス）
ん？
ちょっと信用してもらっただけだよ
I just had him trust me a little.
Don't worry, it's a magnificent drug.
大丈夫 すばらしい薬だよ
So...
（カルタフィルス）だから…
Be a mouse for me.
（カルタフィルス）
僕のためのネズミになってよ
（マシュー）ミナ 大丈夫だよ
（ミナ）うああ！ ああ…
Mina, it's okay.
He said it only hurts in the beginning.
苦しいのは最初だけだって
Hang in there, Mina.
我慢するんだ ミナ
You'll be well after this.
これで元気な体が手に入るんだよ
I'll be with you.
僕がついてる
だから…
So...
Mat... thew...
（ミナ）マ… シュー
あ〜あ 失敗かあ
Oh dear, it failed.
形が崩壊しちゃった
She lost her form.
I suppose beasts are just beasts after all.
やっぱり ケダモノは
ケダモノでしかないのかなあ
They're easier to process than humans,
人間より加工は楽でも
本能が強い分 呪いも強いや
but I guess their strong instincts
means they have strong curses, too.
Looks like I'll have to go back to
figuring out how to condense souls.
魂の凝縮方法の見直しからかな
Thanks for the valuable research data, Mister.
貴重な実験結果をありがとう
おにいさん
Why?
なんで…
ミナ…
Mina...
ミナ… ミナ？
Why, Mina?
どうして ミナ…
ありゃ？ 壊れちゃった
Whoops, he broke.
愛ってすごいね おねえさん
Love's amazing, huh, Miss?
Why?
（マシュー）
どうして どうして どうして…
Why?
Why?!
どうしてええええ！
（マシュー）そうだ
I know.
It wasn't enough.
まだ足りないんだ
I still need more.
More...
もっと
たくさん たくさん たくさん
More,
more.
I need to gather more.
もっと集めないと… 集めないと
I need to gather... more.
もっと…
ああ… ティム
Tim.
I'm glad you're here.
ちょうどいいところに
Your precious Mina is in trouble.
お前の大好きなミナが大変なんだよ
So...
だから…
Okay?
You aren't human anymore.
（ティム）
あんたは もう人間じゃない
あんたは悪魔だ
You're a demon.
悪魔にだまされて
かわいそうな悪魔になっちまった
You were deceived by a demon
into becoming a pitiful demon yourself.
あんたを
生かしておくわけにはいかない
I can't let you live,
and I can't let you die in peace.
安らかに死なせるわけにもいかない
I was chosen to be the king.
こいつらに選ばれた王として
I also do this for those who died.
死んだヤツらのためにもだ
Mina...
（マシュー）
ミナ…
Mina...
ミナ
Where is Mina?
ミナは どこだろう
I'm so lonely without you.
君がいないと さみしいんだ
Mina...
ミナ… ミナ…
Chise.
チセ
I've made you see something terrible, haven't I?
（ミナ）
嫌なものを見せてしまったわね
I only intended to have you erase us,
本当は ただ私たちを
消してもらうだけのはずだったの
but you have a powerful gift of sight.
あなたは視(み)る力が強いのね
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
What do you mean by "erase"?
（チセ）
消すって どういうことですか？
I mean what I said.
言葉どおりよ
Make us not exist.
ないものにするの
The souls of all living things are part of a cycle.
生き物の魂は みんな
巡る輪の中に還(かえ)っていくものなの
でも 私もマシューも
But Matthew and I have forgotten how to return.
そこへの還り方を
忘れてしまったから
猫たちも
As have the cats.
猫たち？
The cats?
殺されて呪いを抱いた猫たちの魂
The souls of the cats who
bore a curse from their murder.
We've all forgotten how to return.
みんな忘れてしまったの　還り方を
So, I want you to erase us.
だから
あなたに私たちを消してほしいの
ダメです！
I can't.
You were only deceived.
あなたたちは
ただ だまされただけで
消してしまうようなものじゃない！
You don't deserve to be erased!
ダメよ… ダメなの
You must.
You have to.
All that waits for us if we lose our chance
now is an even more painful, endless void.
今を逃せば もっと苦しい
終わりのない闇が待ってる
You're the only who can help us right now.
だから 今 あなたにしかできないの
I'll lead the way, then.
（モリィ）
では 私が先導しましょう
（チセ）王様…
King.
This is my ninth life.
（モリィ）私の命は もう９つ目
I'll be returning soon.
じきに還る身の上
I should be able to guide you to where you belong.
私ならば あなたたちを
逝くべき場所へ先導できるのでは？
No!
ダメ！ モリィ あの子が悲しむ！
You can't! That girl will be sad!
Death is always sudden.
（モリィ）死は いつも突然です
平等に 遅かれ早かれ訪れるのです
Sooner or later, it comes to all.
The last king, and the one before,
先の王も その前も皆
澱みを抑えるために
魂を贄(にえ)にしてきました
all sacrificed their souls to hold off the corruption.
Compared to that, being a guide isn't difficult.
それを思うなら
案内役など たやすいことですわ
I have good memories with her.
私には あの子との思い出がある
That's all I need.
それだけで十分ですわ
（ミナ）ありがとう
Thank you.
What should I do?
（チセ）
どうすれば…
（チセ）待って！
Wait.
エアリエル 君なら… 君の力なら
Ariel, with your power,
with the wind to carry seeds far away...
花の種を遠くへ運ぶ風なら…
You're right.
（エアリエル）
そうねン　種は土へ 花は種へ
Seed to soil, flower to seed.
That is the pact of the soil and the wind.
それが土と風の盟約
還るべきものたちは還るべき所へ
Those whose time is to return,
to the place where they must return.
Humans sure are silly and clever. You're amusing.
人間って
おバカで賢くて面白いわねン
That's why we can never get enough of you.
だから アタシたちは
あなたたちから離れられないのン
We won't erase you.
（チセ）消したりなんかしない
Don't worry.
大丈夫 運んでくれる
She'll take you there.
So picture it in your mind.
だから あなたも想像して
Dandelions, sending their seeds off into the air.
タンポポが種を風に乗せるみたいに
そこで芽を出して根づくように
There, they set root and sprout.
The wind blows toward where you need to go.
逝くべき所へ 逝く風が吹くように
Matthew!
（ミナ）マシュー
ミナ！
Mina!
Matthew!
（ミナ）マシュー
Mina.
ああ… ミナ
Where were you?
どこにいたんだい？
マシュー
Matthew.
行きましょう マシュー
Let's go, Matthew.
Thank you, Chise,
ありがとう チセ
the little mage.
小さな魔法使いさん
I pray that you don't come here any time soon.
できれば あなたが
まだ こちらへ来ないよう
祈ってるわ
I was an unnecessary child.
（チセ）
私は いらない子供だった
No one wanted me.
誰にも欲しがられないで
放り出され 転がり続けて
I was kicked out, and I wandered endlessly. And finally...
やっと…
I might've found a perch.
止まり木を
見つけたかもしれないのに
私は いつ死ぬんだろう
When am I going to die?
To keep the seeds I tie to this branch
eda ni musubu mi ga jukusu mae ni
From falling before they ripen
ochite shimawanu you
I bloom again in profusion, painfully
kurushii hodo ni mata sakimidareru
To connect myself to tomorrow.
asa e tsunagu you
Even as they're born again
nando kurikaeshi
And again,
kurikaeshi umaretemo
I'll always show them
itsumo atarashii
A brand new sky.
sora o misete ageyou
I'll pen a story that no one,
daremo mada daremo
No one has ever written.
kaitenai monogatari
On a map so white, pure white,
shiroi masshiroi
I'll draw it out, singing it aloud.
chizu ni kaite utaou
The guiding of souls came at a great cost.
（チセ）
魂の導き
しかし その代償は大きかった
眠りのふちに落ちた少女と
彼女を見守る魔法使い
A girl, on the brink of sleep,
and a mage watching over her.
The two were met by...
２人の前に現れたのは…
Would you introduce me to your wife?
（ティターニア）
お前の妻を紹介してもらえる？